<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on </title>
    <link>https://aniket.io/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aniket.io/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective: 2 years after graduation</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/retrospective-2-years-after-graduation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/retrospective-2-years-after-graduation/</guid>
      <description>May 7th, 2018: I graduated from Arizona State University with a Masters Degree on that day. It&amp;rsquo;s been 2 years since then. This is a retrospective analysis of what worked as planned and what didn&amp;rsquo;t.
And let me tell the current batch of 2020 graduates when I graduated on that day, I did not have any job offer in my hand. I was still applying for jobs all day. Remember, it&amp;rsquo;s will always be dark before the sun rises, but the sun will rise eventually and then there will be light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read it to believe this incredible educational journey</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/read-it-to-believe-this-incredible-educational-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/read-it-to-believe-this-incredible-educational-journey/</guid>
      <description>Educated: A Memoir - Tara Westover About the Book: The book is a memoir of Tara Westover&amp;rsquo;s childhood and her educational leap. Tara was born and raised in Idaho in a family that does not believe in formal education. This shaped a lot of her early childhood. She then went against her own family and enrolled for college at the age of 17, her first formal education. And then this educational journey continued through the halls of Cambridge and Harvard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking done the right way</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/networking-done-the-right-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/networking-done-the-right-way/</guid>
      <description>Exactly one year back, I was a student looking for exciting job opportunities. My idea of networking at that time was to go to a career fair and &amp;lsquo;network&amp;rsquo; with recruiters. Soon I realized that this was not working for me. So I gave up on networking. But after some time, I realized it was working for me in a way I never imagined it would work. It took me almost a year from then to recognize the real power of networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Optional] Things you can do before joining MSBA</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/optional-things-you-can-do-before-joining-msba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/optional-things-you-can-do-before-joining-msba/</guid>
      <description>Hello Incoming Students, Congratulations on your MSBA program admit. You have made it till here, now only nine months of intensive program experience and then you will come out as Data Science Professionals. Yes you heard it right, it is intense, but with proper time management skills, you can pull it off.
So many of you must be thinking, about preparing for the program before joining here, and that’s a great idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final preparations before coming to Phoenix</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/final-preparations-before-coming-to-phoenix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/final-preparations-before-coming-to-phoenix/</guid>
      <description>Hello, Incoming (International) Students, So now you must be getting ready with packing stuff and getting ready for the experience. Check out this comprehensive list of essential things to do that will help you.
Book flight tickets:  The early you book the flight tickets, the cheaper it will be. Usually you get connections from LA or Philadelphia or NY to Phoenix, so in this case, your immigration will happen at the source of entry to the USA, which is LA/Philadelphia/NY in this case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semester 2 in Review</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/semester-2-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/semester-2-in-review/</guid>
      <description>CIS 509: Data Mining 2 This course starts with the necessary programming skills in Python and then building a Recommendation system. Then come to Text Mining and Network Analysis using Python. There are 5 assignments to be submitted in Python code. Towards the end of the course, Big Data Technologies like Hadoop, Kafka, and AWS is taught in brief, with some exercises in AWS as well.
Tools covered: Python, AWS, Hadoop, Kafka</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 40: It’s a wrap!</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-40-its-a-wrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-40-its-a-wrap/</guid>
      <description>2nd May: Marketing Final Exam The exam was at 6 in the evening. The exam was similar to the Assignment patterns. 3 hours, 30 questions, open book, open notes, coding in R and submitting the code as well. The last exam, and then the journey will be finally complete.
Skateboard group: One of the skills I learned here includes Skateboarding. It’s not that easy by the way. Something to try and learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 39: The Penultimate Week</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-39-the-penultimate-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-39-the-penultimate-week/</guid>
      <description>The Presentations Week: Almost all the teams had their Capstone presentations this week, either onsite or on-campus. Also, the Marketing Project Presentation and the Business Venture presentation were in this week. So this was an action-packed week with back to back presentations in all the classes.
MSBA Games: It&amp;rsquo;s almost time for graduation and folks are busy planning for after graduation events and parties. One such includes a Sports Tournament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 38: Time flies so fast</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-38-time-flies-so-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-38-time-flies-so-fast/</guid>
      <description>18th April: The last on-campus career fair: For one last time this spring, a general career fair from 02:00 PM to 04:00 PM at Memorial Union, and again I didn’t have many hopes from this one either. Most companies were looking for sales and marketing executives. However, my room-mate Samarth (also from MSBA) got two interviews scheduled for next day for the position of Business Analyst role and some SCM role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 37: Graduation celebration</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-37-graduation-celebration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-37-graduation-celebration/</guid>
      <description>April 10th: Walmart Supply Chain event Walmart’s Supply Chain team was on campus for recruitment opportunities for a Supply Chain Specialist. They gave a presentation with many key facts on Walmart, and at the end, there was a short online quiz to win prices. Almost 80% of my answers were random guesses, and surprisingly I won 2nd price in this. I received $20 worth of Dominos Pizza Gift Card.
CIS515 Class discussion: We had a class discussion on data privacy concerns created by Facebook, and how it impacts analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 36: The usual affairs</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-36-the-usual-affairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-36-the-usual-affairs/</guid>
      <description>Capstone Projects: It&amp;rsquo;s April now, and almost time to present the deliverable. The good thing is that this time, all students got corporate projects. Many teams are working on Intel projects as well. Many teams are putting in more efforts to get their projects on track and to meet the delivery deadline.
5th April: Data Science Meetup @ Amazon Office, Tempe Dan Petro (ASU MS Computer Science Alumni) presented a session on his work on an AI designed to play the legacy game “Super Smash Bros: Melee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 35: Phoenix Heat is back !</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-35-phoenix-heat-is-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-35-phoenix-heat-is-back/</guid>
      <description>This quarter is very short, only seven weeks and two are already over. Gosh, just around one month left for graduation.
CIS515 Business Analytics Strategy This class had some excellent sessions till now. We discussed on how analytics is changing the landscape of the businesses. We learned how companies are leveraging Analytics, and which opportunities are opening for students with such specialized skillset in Analytics.
This class has take-home quizzes, where we have to read HBR cases to prepare for the quiz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 34: CISCO Circular Economy Challenge</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-34-cisco-circular-economy-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-34-cisco-circular-economy-challenge/</guid>
      <description>23rd March: Cisco Circular Economy Challenge I participated in the Cisco Circular Economy Challenge where we were given an open-ended Circular Economy Challenge, and in 1 week, we were supposed to present a case for a pilot project. I was on a team of some super talented people. Me along with an ASU 2nd year MBA, a MS in Build Environment student from ASU Design School, and one Ph.D. candidate from Walter Cronkite School of Journalism and Mass Communication in ASU and one of my peers in MSBA formed a team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 33: The Final quarter</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-33-the-final-quarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-33-the-final-quarter/</guid>
      <description>12th March: Final quarter commences And so we have reached the final quarter of the program. Time flies so fast. Now only two classes and one capstone project to go, and then we will earn the masters degree.
CIS515 Business Analytics Strategy This class is about how to implement the skills that we have learned till now into a streamlined strategy for an organization. This class is a business course with some focus on Analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 32: Spring Break</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-32-spring-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-32-spring-break/</guid>
      <description>5th March: Devil’s Detour Universal Studios I, Abhishek and Pooja registered for Devil’s Detour to Universal Studios in LA. We left at midnight on Monday 5th March and returned the next midnight. This tour was organized by ASU and is very cheap, compared to the cost of tickets and travel. It was the best use of the spring break time.
Harry Potter world, Transformers, The Mummy, Simpsons, and much more. The Harry Potter ride is the best one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 31: Finals Week</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-31-finals-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-31-finals-week/</guid>
      <description>27th Feb: Capstone Project Interim Presentation Since my Capstone project client outside of Arizona, we only have telephonic meetings. So for the Interim Project presentation was done in front of the Project Mentor only. Just a 15-minute presentation for showcasing the progress and path ahead. Some teams had onsite project presentations as well if the client requested it.
2nd March: Decision Modeling Final Exam 3 of Decision modeling and then we are free for the Spring break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 30: Yet another Career Fair</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-30-yet-another-career-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-30-yet-another-career-fair/</guid>
      <description>20th February: Ira Fulton Engineering Career Fair Ira Fulton Engineering College hosted its career fair at Memorial Union (The building adjacent to McCord Hall) from 19 to 20th February. While most companies were looking for software developers, some were looking for Data Scientists and BI developers as well. There was also a massive queue for each company. Surprisingly, this career fair was better managed than the W.P.Carey Career Fairs. There were proper queue management and even appropriate indicators on each company desk, indicating if the employer had a history of visa sponsorships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 29:  Another Career Fair</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-29-another-career-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-29-another-career-fair/</guid>
      <description>12-14th February: ASU Campus-wide Career and Internship Fair Last Fall, the campus-wide Career Fair was full of Marketing and Sales Job opportunities for the undergrads. So I didn’t have any high hopes for this career fair either. Our MSBA Career Coach shared a list of companies who had openings related to Business Analytics. Most of those companies didn’t send their technical recruiter and most of the companies just ask to apply online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 28:  Google Tech Talk</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-28-google-tech-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-28-google-tech-talk/</guid>
      <description>6th February: Google Tech Talk SoDA (Software Developers Association) organized a Google Lightning Talk, where 3 Googlers were on campus to talk about their experience at Google. They gave some excellent insights on Google. Like they mentioned that Google spends on average 5x more time on reading the code than on writing it, to ensure it is readable (most important) and bug-free. Everyone also received a $50 google cloud credit for free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 27:  Time to apply for OPT</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-27-time-to-apply-for-opt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-27-time-to-apply-for-opt/</guid>
      <description>29th January: Post OPT information session OPT Information sessions are organized by ISSC (International Students and Scholars Center) every semester. It’s almost February and time to start the procedure for OPT work authorization (Applicable to international students only). First, the application goes to ISSC (International Students and Scholars Center) which takes around 10-14 days for the processing of new I-20. The whole procedure is online. Then we have to parcel a bunch of documents and copies to USCIS (U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 26: IoT Dev Fest Arizona 2018</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-26-iot-dev-fest-arizona-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-26-iot-dev-fest-arizona-2018/</guid>
      <description>24th January: Visiting ASU Health Services I missed both the career fairs as I was not well !! So I just received the feedback from the other folks, that the Career Fair was just like the previous one, A lot of hopes and expectations, but nothing regarding opportunities. Companies usually only inform you to apply online.
Medical treatment is costly in the USA, but as students, we have the Aetna Student Insurance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 25: Get well soon</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-25-get-well-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-25-get-well-soon/</guid>
      <description>17th January 2018: The Cold-wave is coming! Until last week, the lowest temperature was about 10 degrees Celsius, but starting this week, looks like some cold wave it hitting Tempe, lowering it to 3 degree Celsius again for a few days. Many folks are even getting sick these days, like widespread coughing around the campus. Maybe be the weather is facilitating the spread of diseases. Also, I caught a cough and fever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 24: Back to school</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-24-back-to-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-24-back-to-school/</guid>
      <description>8th January 2018: And it begins with an excellent day The start of a new semester cannot be more impressive than this. The weather was super fantastic today. Like Fall colors arrived late to Tempe campus. Not too much sunlight, and not even less, it was just perfect. Perfect for pictures as well.
9th January 2018: Rainy Day As per the weather forecast, it will be raining from 09:00 PM, and it did rain around that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 23: Start of something new</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-23-start-of-something-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-23-start-of-something-new/</guid>
      <description>1st week of January: Start of something new It&amp;rsquo;s time to change gears now, first I have been focussed on learning and implementing Data Science skills to build an impressive resume. The second half, for me, will be focused on job hunting. With only a week of vacation left, it&amp;rsquo;s time to roll up the sleeve. This quarter is expected to be not as heavy as Semester 1, because, we now have two-quarter classes each in the two remaining quarters and no more semester-long classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 22: The Year end</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-22-the-year-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-22-the-year-end/</guid>
      <description>Winter break is very useful to rekindle with your long lost hobbies; mine was playing the online multiplayer online game DoTA2. Eventually, I realized that I still suck at this game, with a streak of 10 consecutive match losses. Then participating in some Kaggle competitions to learn Data Science from the real world experts community.
People with a part-time campus job can work more hours in the breaks, so they are enjoying(the money, not extra working hours).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 21: Winter is Coming</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-21-winter-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-21-winter-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>Currently, I don&amp;rsquo;t have any plans to travel around the USA. This winter break, I am planning to learn some skills that would help me in the job-hunting process. W. P. Carey Spring 2018 Information Systems &amp;amp; Business Analytics Career Fair is in January, and I hope to make the best of it. The Machine Learning professor who taught us this semester had some small research kind of projects for students who are available during the winter break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semester 1 in Review</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/semester-1-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/semester-1-in-review/</guid>
      <description>CIS 505: Intro to Enterprise Analytics This course is all about database fundamentals, data modeling, dimensional modeling, visualization, and Business Intelligence. Understanding how and where data is stored in the Enterprise Data Warehouse? SQL is part of the syllabus and is taught from the very basics. The basics of Tableau is also explained in class at the very end. You will need a lot of practice (other than class time) to master both skills: SQL and Tableau.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 20: And the Last Exam</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-20-and-the-last-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-20-and-the-last-exam/</guid>
      <description>11th December: Race Day As part of the Data-Driven Quality Management class project, we were supposed to design a LEGO set car that would travel the longest distance off the ramp. We were supposed to use Design of Experiments concepts that we learned in the class. And if this was not interesting enough, we had a Race Day where we would be competing with other teams in the cohort to win the Prize of the Best car design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 19: And Another exam</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-19-and-another-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-19-and-another-exam/</guid>
      <description>3rd December: ASU Police Alert Although Tempe is a very safe place to live, some things can happen. This thing was a once in a blue moon event. I received an ASU Police Alert of some robbery suspects roaming in Tempe at night around 11:00 PM. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what happened next, but I am sure this was not a piece of big news the next day. Rest assured, Tempe is a very safe city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 18: Final Exam Commencement</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-18-final-exam-commencement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-18-final-exam-commencement/</guid>
      <description>Sunday 26th November: War Room (Team Meet) We desperately needed a Team Meeting (War room meeting) to discuss pending team items for submission. We listed out all the upcoming presentations and quizzes for the MSBA program. We then tacked the assignments one by one. We went home late that day (9:00 PM), and it was getting remarkably cold. It’s time to replace a sweater with a thick jacket, especially while cycling at night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 17: Black Friday</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-17-black-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-17-black-friday/</guid>
      <description>21st November: Thanksgiving lunch at W.P.Carey It’s time for the 2nd Festival (1st is Diwali) to be celebrated by the school. My American friends explained the tradition of drawing a turkey and thanking for all the things, and then you can have the Thanksgiving lunch. There were some turkey and some mashed potato dish and for the desert – the traditional Pumpkin Pie. It was a tasty meal to get indulged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 16: International Night</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-16-international-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-16-international-night/</guid>
      <description>13th Nov: Guest lecture by Point b ‘Point b’ is a consultancy firm based in the USA. Executives from the company came to our class of Data-Driven Quality Management to explain some case studies that they had worked on. They also had freebies for who even answered their questions and also if you ask a good question. It’s a great way to understand what a consulting firm does and how it implements solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 15: Kaggle.com</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-15-kaggle.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-15-kaggle.com/</guid>
      <description>6th November: Data Analytics Club Data Analytics Club of ASU has a meet on most Mondays at McCord Hall. Undergrad students run this organization from Computer Science Majors or Data Analytics Major. Today they had a session on Web scrapping using &amp;ldquo;scrapy&amp;rdquo; - the web scrapping library in python. The meeting was interactive with the ongoing live demo. This club is not very popular, so its attendees strength is also quite low, I guess it has to do with the lack of publicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 14: W.P.(Scary Halloween)</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-14-w.p.scary-halloween/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-14-w.p.scary-halloween/</guid>
      <description>October 31st: Halloween I was in the MGT class, and suddenly, 5 minutes into the session, the Dark Lord of Sith entered along with Goku. Welcome to the Halloween Night.
I and my roommates headed to Mill Avenue( The most happening place in Tempe). The streets were crowded, with ghosts and demons and whatnot. Scary jokers and clowns everywhere.
2nd November: Diwali Night W.P.Carey school celebrates three festivals around the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 13: Start of Quarter 2</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-13-start-of-quarter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-13-start-of-quarter-2/</guid>
      <description>23rd October: Intel Deep Learning Event Classes finally started after a long break. Morning temperatures are quite low now (around 17-19degree celsius). Also, since Arizona’s Mountain Time Zone (MST) does not accommodate for daylight savings, it gets dark around 6 PM itself. Even when returning home at around 9 PM, the weather is cold and pleasant, unlike the heat in the afternoon.
In the evening, we somehow came to know about the Intel DeepLearning Event on the ASU campus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 12: Fall Break</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-12-fall-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-12-fall-break/</guid>
      <description>Fall Break is a 1-week break that relieves you from all the assignments and homework for a short time. I decided to visit the Grand Canyon for this break. Also luckily this holiday overlapped with the Indian Festival of Diwali, making this holiday exciting.
16th, 17th October: The Grand Canyon 10 folks | 2 cars | 2Days-1Night | Flagstaff | Grand Canyon | Horseshoe bend | Lower Antilope Canyon.
19th October: Laxmi Pujan Diwali celebrations in the USA are quite different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 11: And the exams continue</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-11-and-the-exams-continue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-11-and-the-exams-continue/</guid>
      <description>9th October: Intro to Enterprise Analytics Final Exam A 2-hour exam with multiple-choice questions and SQL queries. We were given access to the SQL database and had questions to generate queries. MCQ’s were quite comfortable, and the queries took some time. Overall I was able to complete it way before 2 hours limit.
10th October: Data-Driven Quality Management Take-home exam The Data-Driven Quality Management professor gave us the midterm exam as a take-home exam to be repeated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10: Outside my comfort zone</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-10-outside-my-comfort-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-10-outside-my-comfort-zone/</guid>
      <description>2nd October: Data-Driven Quality Management Midterm Our professor had already informed us, he had set an exam where he expects us to get around 75% only. And he had also intimated us that it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be easy. All the earlier tests I took were not that challenging at all, and in most of the class tests in other subjects, it&amp;rsquo;s quite easy to score. Till today everything was going very easy, and this was about to change today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 09: Quarter end study preparation</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-09-quarter-end-study-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-09-quarter-end-study-preparation/</guid>
      <description>W.P.Carey School has a curriculum system which includes quarter based subjects and semester-based subjects, and the 1st quarter is about to end, we have exams next week. For the quarter subject &amp;ldquo;Intro to Enterprise Analytics,&amp;rdquo; we have the final exam, and for other semester-based subjects, we have our midterm.
There is no fixed pattern of exams and marks structure. Each professor is empowered to design the model of exams, class tests, and marking structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 08: The Career Fair</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-08-the-career-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-08-the-career-fair/</guid>
      <description>18th September: McCord Hall has an impressive lounge with multiple Fridges and microwaves. It also has some seating area for having lunch. If you are lucky, you might even find free food over here. Hence it’s always a good idea to check this lounge whenever passing by this area. I was studying here today in the evening and got slices of free cheese pizza. There is usually leftover food from events across McCord Hall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 07: MSBA Student Ambassador</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-07-msba-student-ambassador/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-07-msba-student-ambassador/</guid>
      <description>12th September: SoDA coding competition I, along with my team, attended the SoDA coding competition hosted by Google on campus today. It was precisely for software engineering. It was an hour-long session of coding challenges, and I was not even able to solve one problem, to my defense, I must say they were very tough challenges. The 2nd round was not related to coding, it was related to guessing games, we had to guess nodes in a graph, where some clues nodes are placed to help you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 06: And the course catches pace</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-06-and-the-course-catches-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-06-and-the-course-catches-pace/</guid>
      <description>4th September: Classes and classes It&amp;rsquo;s very advantageous if you have some industry experience in any related field. I had experience in Business Intelligence and Data Warehousing, so the subject &amp;ldquo;Introduction to Enterprise Analytics&amp;rdquo; was entirely relatable for me. Some of my friends had experience in SQL, which helped them a lot.
Assignments and homework start to pile up, so it becomes a priority to get it done in team meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 05: McKesson networking event</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-05-mckesson-networking-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-05-mckesson-networking-event/</guid>
      <description>28th August: McKesson Recruitment and Networking Event I, with a few friends, attended half of the morning class and then left during the mid-break as we had to travel to Phoenix for the McKesson event, which was at 2:00 PM. We took Lyft cab to the destination, Galvanize building in Phoenix. We got ourselves registered there and met a few employees from McKesson. They were ASU undergraduate students doing a part-time internship in McKesson in their cybersecurity division.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 04: Classes Commence</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-04-classes-commence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-04-classes-commence/</guid>
      <description>21st August: Classes commence The educational system is entirely different in the USA. Here a discussion-based class is encouraged rather than a delivery based class. In a delivery based class, the professor delivers the knowledge to all the students. I have experienced this in my earlier educational system in India. This is a one-directional flow of knowledge. Instead, here they follow the discussion-based model, where the professor hands out the notes and reading materials before the classes for the students to read and come prepared to the class to participate in discussions actively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 03: India Day</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-03-india-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-03-india-day/</guid>
      <description>14th August 2017: Starting at 5:00 PM local time (15th August in India), we had an India Day celebration in ASU organized by ISA(Indian Student Association). There was quite a substantial Indian crowd here. Current students, as well as some Alumni, also joined the event. There was a Quiz booth, Mehendi Booth, and Karaoke booth as well. There was also free food, which included Veg and Non-Veg Biryani, Samosa, and Gulab Jamun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 02: The MSBA Orientation</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-02-the-msba-orientation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-02-the-msba-orientation/</guid>
      <description>7th and 8th August: We had our program orientation, which is for the Master of Science in Business Analytics program. We were instructed to be dressed in Business Professional suits for Monday, as they would be taking our photos for the yearbook. Then again, we had some sessions on Academic Integrity, emphasizing its importance. A few domestic students also joined us from Today. We had an Alumni Panel, where Shaunak Bangale, along with a few other alumni, shared their views, followed by motivation and encouragement for our upcoming journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 01: Surviving the heat</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/week-01-surviving-the-heat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/week-01-surviving-the-heat/</guid>
      <description>30th July: We got out of the airport at 9:00 PM; it was hot outside. Damn! If it&amp;rsquo;s this hot at night, then how hot will it be in the afternoon, I thought to myself. We had free rides to our accommodation, which was sponsored by ASU. A friend and I were to stay at my friend&amp;rsquo;s friend&amp;rsquo;s place, as our rented accommodation move-in date was two days away.
When we reached the place, I just sat on a chair and was thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the journey begins</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/and-the-journey-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/and-the-journey-begins/</guid>
      <description>A 30-hour journey. Three layovers. 3 countries: India(Mumbai) -&amp;gt; UK(London) -&amp;gt; USA(Philadelphia, Phoenix). It all started with some emotional goodbyes at the airport. I was nervous and a bit scared of leaving the comfort zone, and at the same time, excited as well for the challenges that lie ahead.
 &amp;ldquo;The best things in life are often waiting for you at the exit ramp of your comfort zone.&amp;rdquo; – Karen Salmansohn</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The VISA Interview</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/the-visa-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/the-visa-interview/</guid>
      <description>After some 5-6 basic questions and then later typing something on the keyboard, the VISA interviewer asked which looked like the final question, “Do you have plans to return to India?” to which I instantly replied with an affirmative answer “Yes.” Then he seemed to start again typing a few things, and then he finally said something. I only remember the part where he said, “You can collect your passport later; you will get an SMS when it’s ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The W.P.Carey Mumbai Reception!</title>
      <link>https://aniket.io/the-w.p.carey-mumbai-reception/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aniket.io/the-w.p.carey-mumbai-reception/</guid>
      <description>April 30th, 2017, The day to meet my fellow peers at the W.P.Carey School of Business at Arizona State University organized Reception in Mumbai. The location was J W Marriott, Juhu, Mumbai. The dress code was Business Casuals. It started as a networking event for all the future students gathered there.
There was a session where the course coordinators described the journey ahead and some aspects of life in Tempe, which is awaiting us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>